<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Tired Energy</title>
        <link>https://tired.energy/</link>
        <description>Recent content on Tired Energy</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 06:50:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tired.energy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Adhd - a Metaphor</title>
        <link>https://tired.energy/p/adhd-a-metaphor/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 21:39:46 -0600</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://tired.energy/p/adhd-a-metaphor/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://tired.energy/p/adhd-a-metaphor/sascha-bosshard-HRldvxTg6nM-unsplash.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post Adhd - a Metaphor" /&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;lets-imagine-executive-function-as-a-bowl-of-cereal-every-decision-that-needs-to-be-made-fun-or-arduous-requires-you-to-eat-the-whole-bowl-of-cereal&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s imagine executive function as a bowl of cereal. Every decision that needs to be made, fun or arduous, requires you to eat the whole bowl of cereal.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a child, you crunched through your cereal when your parents asked you too, but it hurt and you didn&amp;rsquo;t enjoy it. Everyone around you was eating their cereal just fine and didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be in any pain at all. You told people you didn&amp;rsquo;t like eating the cereal, that it was too difficult, and that it hurt to eat. Teachers and family members insisted that &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;You just need to try harder to eat the cereal!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; but it didn&amp;rsquo;t matter how hard you tried, it still was difficult and painful. Fun activities and enjoyable experiences required multiple bowls of cereal to get through and you never managed to complete them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you got older, you realized that everyone else had milk in their cereal which made it possible to eat without pain. You looked in your fridge, but you didn&amp;rsquo;t have any milk there. Everyone else seemed to always wake up with a fresh gallon of milk in the fridge each day, and could eat many bowls of cereal before the milk ran out. You tried to force yourself to eat cereal, but each day you could only get through a couple before the pain was too much and you stopped eating entirely to give your bleeding mouth a rest. Remembering and being able to do homework from school takes more bowls of cereal than you can eat, and your parents and teachers get upset with you. Frustrated with your inability to eat enough cereal, they keep you after school and give you work to do while setting a bowl of cereal in front of you and staring at you while you eat it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;See? You can eat cereal just fine! Now just do this yourself every day.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You try to explain that you don&amp;rsquo;t have any milk in your fridge, but they don&amp;rsquo;t seem to understand. They are also too proud of themselves for getting you to eat that bowl of cereal to really listen to what you are saying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reaching your teenage years, you begin to find ways of imitating the milk. You pour different liquids into your cereal, but that only helps a little and everyone can tell that your cereal is different. You still can&amp;rsquo;t eat as many bowls as everyone else, and society seems to be designed for people who can eat many bowls of cereal every day. You discover that if you pour alcohol in your cereal, it still doesn&amp;rsquo;t taste good and it still hurts, but you don&amp;rsquo;t feel the pain from it as much. It&amp;rsquo;s also easier to handle the embarrassment of not eating as many bowls of cereal as everyone expects you to eat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After many years, you hear about doctors who specialize in people who struggle to eat cereal. It takes a lot of bowls of cereal to find a doctor near you, schedule an appointment, and remember to go. And this is only possible when you&amp;rsquo;ve successfully forced enough bowls of painful cereal down to get and maintain a job which provides health insurance to pay for the doctor. Between first hearing about these doctors and actually being in the first appointment it&amp;rsquo;s been almost 5 years. You talk with the doctor about all of your struggles eating cereal due to not having any milk appear in your fridge each morning. Fortunately, this doctor isn&amp;rsquo;t one of the ones who believe that when you turn 18 you magically start finding milk in the fridge each morning. The doctor tells you that there is therapy specifically designed to help you. He also explains to you that he can authorize you to order a delivery of a half-gallon of milk each morning from a pharmacy nearby. It needs to be authorized because some people, who naturally get a gallon of milk in their fridge each day, are getting extra cartons of milk and chugging them right out of the carton until they get sick or cause problems for others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;robin-worrall-H5Y2Nb8hreU-unsplash.jpeg&#34;
         alt=&#34;Glass of millk and books&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
                    &lt;a href=&#34;https://unsplash.com/photos/H5Y2Nb8hreU&#34;&gt;Photo by Robin Worrall&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cautiously optimistic, you arrange for the milk delivery. The first day it arrives, you pour yourself a bowl of cereal, fill it with milk, take your first bite, and&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;holy-crap-it-doesnt-hurt&#34;&gt;Holy Crap! It doesn&amp;rsquo;t hurt!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You dance for joy and start to do the things that you&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to do, but were locked behind multiple bowls of cereal. They&amp;rsquo;re not crazy activities, in fact they&amp;rsquo;re activities most people do regularly. But you treasure these activities because now you can actually eat the required amount of cereal without any pain. Reauthorizing the milk deliveries each month is annoying and requires using some of the previous month&amp;rsquo;s milk, but you&amp;rsquo;re happy to do so because it means you can begin to have some semblance of a &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>First Things First - I&#39;m Tired</title>
        <link>https://tired.energy/p/first-things-first-im-tired/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 21:28:40 -0600</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://tired.energy/p/first-things-first-im-tired/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://tired.energy/p/first-things-first-im-tired/kate-stone-matheson-uy5t-CJuIK4-unsplash.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post First Things First - I&#39;m Tired" /&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;it-was-september-2018-and-i-was-asleep-in-my-car&#34;&gt;It was September 2018, and I was asleep in my car.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was in southern Minnesota, surrounded by corn, and parked next to a field that would soon become a 1 MW solar farm. It was 11 AM and I was waiting for the civil contractors to show up with the surveyor to stake out the perimeter of the site. I had my &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo; work laptop open on the passenger seat of my Honda Civic coupe as my head kept nodding forward, with each nod lasting longer and longer until the I was woken up by a car horn. The civil contractors had pulled up in their work truck right across from me and were chuckling as I started awake. They drove up next to me and rolled down their window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Took a nap waiting for us? I don&amp;rsquo;t blame ya!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They clearly weren&amp;rsquo;t upset and found it to be a sensible chuckle. &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re not going to bring our crew here today, ground&amp;rsquo;s about to be to wet and muddy.&amp;rdquo; I looked up at the sky and sure enough the clear sky had turned dark gray while I was snoozing, which meant an autumn downpour was on the way. As the contractors drove off, I was embarrassed but glad that nothing detrimental came from falling asleep in the middle of the day. I berated myself and swore that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t let my daytime exhaustion ruin things this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Three months prior to this,&lt;/strong&gt; I watched 75% of my coworkers get laid off from Tesla&amp;rsquo;s solar division and realized exactly how &amp;ldquo;stable&amp;rdquo; my job was. I was grateful that I managed to avoid this fate, as I enjoyed doing solar sales and I particularly enjoyed having health insurance. Unfortunately, this restructuring turned a 15 minute commute in South Jersey (southern New Jersey) into an hour and a half drive through Philadelphia to King of Prussia. I was asked to train the car salespeople at the Tesla store in the mall how to sell solar to the people who wandered in from the Apple store next door. Tired of 8 shots of espresso a day to make it through the drive and the 8 hours in a mall, I began looking for another option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;kevin-butz-BBFRIGifYQ8-unsplash.jpeg&#34;
         alt=&#34;Two shots of espresso&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
                    &lt;a href=&#34;https://unsplash.com/photos/BBFRIGifYQ8&#34;&gt;Photo by Kevin Butz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reached out to a friend who was doing O&amp;amp;M work on utility-scale solar farms to see if he could help me find a job on the construction side of the solar industry. Did I know that O&amp;amp;M meant Operations and Maintenance? Absolutely not. All I knew was that I wanted to stay in the solar industry, and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t keep going with what I was doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This company that my buddy worked for was looking for construction managers to go onsite and oversee the building of 1 MW solar farms in southern Minnesota. Sure it might be a job I&amp;rsquo;ve never done, in a place I&amp;rsquo;ve never been, but a change of pace sounded real pleasant to me. 3 phone interviews, 24 sugar-free Monster energy drinks, and 1,212 miles later I pulled into a Motel6 in Mankato, Minnesota. It was mid-August 2018 and I was ready to build some renewable energy, find my passion, and probably save the world from climate change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Main character syndrome much?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-following-bit-is-a-sidebar-into-health-insurance-and-what-it-meant-for-me-to-be-working-as-a-contractor&#34;&gt;The following bit is a sidebar into health insurance and what it meant for me to be working as a contractor.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now an important point to note here is that I was going from full-time (but not great pay) to working as a contractor. And as is standard in America, that meant going to a job with no healthcare benefits. For anyone reading who isn&amp;rsquo;t familiar with America&amp;rsquo;s health care situation, health care is provided by health insurance companies. Per the 2020 US Census&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, 8.6% of people, or 28.0 million, did not have health insurance at any point during the year. Additionally, 54.4% percent of people have employment-based health insurance. What this means isn&amp;rsquo;t that you get free health care due to being employed, what it means is that your employer chooses a health insurance company and plan, and then they (potentially) cover a portion of the monthly premium. You, as the employee, are responsible for the rest of the monthly premium in addition to the deductible (the first $xxxx of qualified health care expenses). Once you meet your deductible the health insurance company will pay a percentage of your health care expense for the remainder of the calendar year, and if your employer has chosen a good plan it might even be 100%!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;diana-polekhina-F68HtpYHu_w-unsplash.jpeg&#34;
         alt=&#34;Two latex gloved thumbs up&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
                    &lt;a href=&#34;https://unsplash.com/photos/F68HtpYHu_w&#34;&gt;Photo by Diana Polekhina&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now hold on, don&amp;rsquo;t get too excited here!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your health insurance company is only going to cover the full amount if you go to medical providers who are considered &lt;em&gt;in-network&lt;/em&gt;. In-network means that the health insurance company and the medical provider have already spoken and decided to work together and bill each other in a certain, agreed-upon manner. How do you know if a doctor you see is network? You don&amp;rsquo;t! Some doctors will say that they &amp;ldquo;likely&amp;rdquo; are in-network for you, but they can&amp;rsquo;t say for sure. You can call your health insurance company to find out, but that process is incredibly complex and time-consuming. You better hope you don&amp;rsquo;t have any medical emergencies come up outside of business hours or where you don&amp;rsquo;t have the time to call the insurance company. Additionally, this network is usually centered in a specific geographic area where the health insurance company is headquartered. What happens if you work a job that involves you traveling to different parts of the country, like if you are building solar farms? Good luck, because it&amp;rsquo;s impossible to predict whether you will have any options!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the really fun part:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lose or change your job? Lose or change your health insurance. Now there are some programs like COBRA&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; where you can continue on your existing plan for 18 - 36 months after losing health coverage from your employer, but you are now responsible for the entirety of the premium (often twice what you were paying previously) plus a 2% administrative fee! Setting aside the fact that this situation creates a very easily exploitable power dynamic between employer and employee, the idea that you could lose health coverage at any time encourages people to avoid going to a doctor over anything that isn&amp;rsquo;t urgent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;ok-back-to-the-story&#34;&gt;Ok back to the story.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There I was - freshly employed as a contractor, freshly uninsured, and with a fresh thermos of coffee (extra strong!) in hand. I walked into the field from the shoulder of the road where I parked my car and met my new boss Paul. He gave me my work laptop (it had an old i3, 4GB of RAM, and was slow as lazy molasses) and a bunch of documentation on how a solar generation plant, also known as a solar farm, is built. After a few hours we took a break for lunch, and then I spent the rest of my day reading documentation at the hotel and accidentally taking a nap in the late afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day I spend the morning at the project of another site manager named Mark. This site was about 15 miles closer to the hotel from the one I was to be managing, and I was only about 5 minutes late due to waking up like a rock. Mark was an older fellow and he had a decent bit of experience managing solar sites previously, so he showed me the &amp;ldquo;company way&amp;rdquo; of completing processes. This involved being cranky at subcontractors, inspecting installations, yelling at the computer, and taking photos of all documentation and work. I decided to only imitate &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; of the processes at my project site - I&amp;rsquo;m don&amp;rsquo;t really care for being cranky or yelling at things, life is too short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;MN-in-day.jpeg&#34;
         alt=&#34;Ethan in a hardhat with solar construction behind his left shoulder&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Look I&amp;rsquo;m onsite in MN!&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first day fully &amp;ldquo;on my own&amp;rdquo; I woke up and drove the 40 minutes from my extended stay hotel to the project site, which at this point was just an empty field that had all the corn harvested already. I waited for the civil subcontractors to show and start clearing the site, drank coffee by the barrel, and tried not to fall asleep. I also began working my way through an online training course on Solar Electric Design and Installation&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; (Shout out SEI!). This established the normal structure of my days for the next couple weeks - drag myself out of bed, meet subcontractors on site, consume as much caffeine as possible, and learn more about solar installation and design. I was always walking around the site as much as possible, which helped to stave off the waves of exhaustion that would come over me. This helped me keep an eye on the subcontractors progress as well, which was quite important to keeping them on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a couple weeks, there was a sizable change to my routine - I got an office on the project site. Well technically it was an office made from a Conex. For anyone who isn&amp;rsquo;t aware, a Conex is essentially a shipping container with windows, a door, lights, and desk for the construction plan-sets. Now, in my new luxury accommodations, I would be able to focus and be more awake and&amp;hellip; oops I fell asleep in the chair again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;id-like-to-pause-here-and-go-into-a-little-detail-about-what-was-going-on-when-i-say-that-i-fell-asleep&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to pause here and go into a little detail about what was going on when I say that I &amp;ldquo;fell asleep.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These events would happen when I was sitting, but only when I wasn&amp;rsquo;t driving (apparently this is due to the fact that focused driving engages the same parts of my body &amp;amp; brain as physical activity such as walking). It would usually occur when I was doing something like reading emails. I would get hit by these waves of exhaustion, that hit my whole body in a very sudden manner. First I would feel a wave of &lt;em&gt;sensation&lt;/em&gt; go from my feet to my head, which was like I could feel every part of my body more intensely. If I stood up at this point and started walking around, that would stave off the wave for a while. Next, my muscles would go slightly weak, my eyelids would start to droop, and my head would start to nod forward. At this point, it was like my brain was screaming at me &amp;ldquo;GO TO SLEEP NOW! GO TO SLEEP NOW!&amp;rdquo; If I didn&amp;rsquo;t do anything, I would fall asleep for about 4 minutes, suddenly jerk awake, look around to see what was happening, fall back asleep again, and repeat that whole process up to 10 times. I later learned that what I was experiencing was called a Sleep Attack, which is a very apt way to describe the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;ok-back-to-building-solar-farms-in-southern-mn&#34;&gt;Ok back to building solar farms in southern MN.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over time I learned that if I took a focused and intentional 15-minute nap, then I would wake up far more awake and refreshed than if I tried to fight the wave of exhaustion for an hour. Eventually I found out that this is an actual doctor recommended solution, but at the time I felt so guilty about it. I would lock the office trailer door, look out the windows to make sure everything was ok, and then hide on the floor under the plan-sets desk. In this hidden alcove, I would set my alarm for 15 minutes, use my hoodie as a pillow, and try my hardest to leave all of my exhaustion behind in that nap. I also learned that going to the gym at night gave me a tiny bit of a boost of energy the next day, so I started going every day. So between the 6 energy drinks or coffees a day, going to the gym, and taking intentional naps, I had a system that worked well enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A really interesting part of these sleep attacks was the fact that as I was in that state of almost asleep and almost awake, I would have crazy half-dreams about my current environment. &lt;strong&gt;These usually resulted in me having some flash of insight that would help me solve a problem I was struggling with.&lt;/strong&gt; Even now, with my sleep disorders well-managed, I still have those moments of sudden inspiration where I make a connection between concepts that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have thought of otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I truly believe is that humans can adapt to any situation, and I was a prime example of this. Over the following months, I got really good at managing upwards of 50 subcontractors and learning more about PV systems while having these wild sleep attacks. The first 1 MW project was running behind due to weather delays and subcontractor staffing issues, but I got them across the finish line with weekend shifts, free pizza, and staying late holding flashlights for the electricians. I then finished two additional projects in southern MN where the site managers had quit. I also went out to operating solar farms with my electrician buddy who got me the job in the first place, to do the Operations and Maintenance (O&amp;amp;M) work on some solar sites in western MN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This whole time I was doing more online certification courses about solar design and installation and &lt;strong&gt;I. Could. Not. Get. Enough.&lt;/strong&gt; It was the coolest information and it all fit together so well in my mind, it was like I was &lt;em&gt;meant&lt;/em&gt; to learn this stuff! Solar power began to make so much sense to me because:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solar farms are power plants where the fuel (sunlight) is delivered to you each day, for free! And they use magic rocks (silicon) to turn that fuel into pure electricity, with no smokestacks or radiation! It almost sounds like something from a fantasy novel, but it&amp;rsquo;s just great science being implemented well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was getting colder every day that we went out to a site, and I was beginning to understand what a Minnesota Winter really was. As were my poor toes, fingers and nose! As it neared the end of December, the company asked if I would like to go down to Georgia and manage the construction of a larger 3.4 MW site that was about to be installed. I took a look at the forecast for MN the first week of January, saw a high of -4°F, and started packing my car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1,212 miles east to my house in southern NJ. Pause for 2 days to drop off super cold weather clothes and grab normal cold weather clothes. 702 miles south to Augusta, GA. Meet subcontractors. Nap when possible. Become one with caffeine. Learn more. Repeat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the project in Georgia successfully came to a close, the CEO of the company came to visit the site with the Georgia Public Service Commission (we needed to make them happy). He and I got to talking about my background with Tesla, and about energy storage in the residential sector. It came up that the company had a new product they wanted to develop and release, and it seemed like I might be a good fit to head that up. He came back to give me a more in depth summary of the product and interviewed me for the role. After a couple weeks of anxious waiting, I found out that they were going to make me an offer! I was thrilled, this was a cool product and it would mean I would work out of the company&amp;rsquo;s main office just outside of Atlanta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most importantly&amp;hellip; it was a full time position with benefits!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point I knew that I needed health care so that I could take care of a number of different issues I was going through. I was most concerned about my ADHD, which I felt was impacting my life quite significantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oh yeah, not sure if I mentioned that, but I also have ADHD - which is nearly as impactful as my sleep disorders.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was &lt;strong&gt;so&lt;/strong&gt; ready when the day came to sign the offer letter and employment contract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;scott-graham-OQMZwNd3ThU-unsplash.jpeg&#34;
         alt=&#34;Signing a contract&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
                    &lt;a href=&#34;https://unsplash.com/photos/OQMZwNd3ThU&#34;&gt;Photo by Scott Graham&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started the full time role that summer (2019) and immediately started setting up doctor appointments as fast as I could. Once I was able to get the medication I needed for my ADHD, a lot of my exhaustion went away. I found out later that there is a lot of overlap with the medications prescribed for ADHD and those prescribed for Narcolepsy/Excessive Daytime Sleepiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With my ADHD and sleepiness somewhat managed, I was able to really step into my new role and accomplish a lot while also learning a ton. I got a prototype system together, bought a house to test it at, installed the prototype, wrote patent language for our application, vetted and secured manufacturers for the components, and designed a new electrical switching mechanism for the system. I also passed my NABCEP PV Installation Professional&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; certification exam - the premier certification in the solar industry. In the beginning of 2020, I also learned to code so that I could program the remote data acquisition and control software for the product. As we began to roll out the new product and start marketing and sales, I also wrote a piece of software to model any homeowner&amp;rsquo;s hourly electrical usage and compare it to different sizes of the solar and storage system our product offered. The software then would generate a complete proposal for the homeowner, including charts of backup power usage and battery SoC across the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of those things wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been possible without the health insurance and medical treatment I had. There was still a problem however. I was still getting tired and would be able to nap, even after taking the ADHD medication. Was it better than I was before? Absolutely! Was there still something going on? &lt;strong&gt;Definitely.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know that getting better was possible, I eventually managed to get an appointment with a sleep specialist in the Atlanta area towards the end of 2020. After my initial conversation with the doctor, they were pretty sure that I had Narcolepsy based on the fact that I have been falling asleep at random times since I was a kid. The first step to confirm this was a sleep study. They hooked me up to a ton of equipment and monitors and had me sleep in their facility overnight. Assuming that they didn&amp;rsquo;t find any sleep apnea, I would then stay the next day for the MSLT (nap test).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Sleep-Study.jpeg&#34;
         alt=&#34;Ethan with wires and sensors on at his sleep study&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;I felt like an android&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the technicians woke me up that morning, they told me that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to stay for the nap test due to my results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What were my results?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have severe Obstructive Sleep Apnea. A score of 39.9. As my doctor explained to me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obstructive Sleep Apnea means that your body physically blocks off your airway while you are asleep, and then choke until your body finally gasps awake. Many people, like me, never remember partially waking up choking. This partial awakening is incredibly disruptive to your quality of sleep. A score of 39.9 means that, on average, for every 60 minutes of sleep, I would stop breathing and gasp awake 39 point 9 times. &lt;strong&gt;Essentially 2 out of every 3 minutes I would stop breathing and wake up.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holy. Crap. That certainly would explain a lot! Glad to finally have learned this information, I earned the privilege to pay for a CPAP machine (because of course health insurance wouldn&amp;rsquo;t cover the whole thing). This positive air pressure machine created enough air pressure in my lungs and throat so that my score dropped down below 5. I was thrilled! I was also &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;STILL TIRED.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After speaking to the doctor again, I had joy of doing Sleep Study 2: 2 Sleep 2 Tired. This time, using my CPAP machine, I was able to make it through to the MSLT the next day. This test consisted of 5 set times throughout the day where I would be given the opportunity to sleep. During each nap period they would check how quickly I fell asleep, if at all, and whether I entered REM sleep when I slept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gotta say it was pretty great to have a day where all I was expected to do was take naps! And I sure did nap, falling asleep and going into REM in each period. Two weeks later I had my next appointment with the sleep specialist and I got the results - Narcolepsy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for those of you keeping track at home, for the first 29 years of my life I was combatting these disorders, completely unmanaged and untreated:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Narcolepsy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sleep Apnea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ADHD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wow.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days, with the help of some excellent doctors, everything I was battling is now well-managed and appropriately treated. And you know what? I&amp;rsquo;m honestly proud of myself. I fought so hard to get where I am, not even realizing that I was going through things that many people never have to deal with. I refused to quit and fought to keep putting one foot in front of the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;rsquo;m really tired. Not as much physically anymore, but I&amp;rsquo;m certainly tired of oil and gas companies destroying our planet. I&amp;rsquo;m tired of governments and corporations destroying our future, just for a few more dollars of short-term profit. I&amp;rsquo;m tired of hearing the same old sayings from the same old people - &amp;ldquo;We can&amp;rsquo;t change too quickly&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;What about the economy&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;We need to worry about the next election&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;We can&amp;rsquo;t overhaul the electrical grid&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;We &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; oil and gas&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;We can&amp;rsquo;t make all vehicles electric&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not profitable to use sustainable practices&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I fought so hard to get where I am today, and I&amp;rsquo;m going to keep fighting to create the best future we can.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-may-be-tired-but-i-am-full-of-energy-and-im-going-to-use-it-to-advance-awesome-renewable-technology-to-connect-people-with-incredible-ideas-for-sustainability-to-find-ways-to-prevent-greed-and-business-as-usual-from-destroying-our-world&#34;&gt;I may be Tired, but I am full of Energy and I&amp;rsquo;m going to use it to advance awesome renewable technology, to connect people with incredible ideas for sustainability, to find ways to prevent greed and business-as-usual from destroying our world.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Health Insurance Coverage in the United States: 2020 by Katherine Keisler-Starkey and Lisa N. Bunch, Issued September 2021 P60-274 - &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.census.gov/content/dam/Census/library/publications/2021/demo/p60-274.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continuation of Health Coverage (COBRA), Employee Benefits Security Administration, Labor, Final Rules Published 2004-05-26 - &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.dol.gov/general/topic/health-plans/cobra&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PVOL101: SOLAR TRAINING - SOLAR ELECTRIC DESIGN AND INSTALLATION (GRID-DIRECT) - ONLINE, SEI.com - &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.solarenergy.org/courses/solar-training-solar-electric-design-and-installation-grid-direct-online/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;North American Board of Certified Energy Practitioners - &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.nabcep.org/certifications/nabcep-board-certifications/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>About</title>
        <link>https://tired.energy/about/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://tired.energy/about/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;hi-there-my-name-is-ethan-im-a-product-manager-with-4-years-of-experience-in-the-solar-and-energy-storage-industry&#34;&gt;Hi there! My name is Ethan. I&amp;rsquo;m a product manager, with 4 years of experience in the solar and energy storage industry.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am neurodiverse and narcoleptic, and this blog is about human experiences - in the renewables field and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be sharing my stories, conversations with good people in the industry, new ideas and technologies that could be industry-defining, and more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intersection of technology, people, and energy is incredibly engaging to me, and you can see this reflected in my &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/etsea117&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;. I explore blockchain, app development, data analysis and more. (BTW, I know my code is spaghetti - your feedback is greatly valued!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love the phenomonal role I have as a software product manager at one of the largest independent renewable energy companies in the world! Although that gives me unique perspective and experience - everything on this site is my own personal opinions and is not necessarily reflective of the views of my company.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Archives</title>
        <link>https://tired.energy/archives/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://tired.energy/archives/</guid>
        <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Search</title>
        <link>https://tired.energy/search/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://tired.energy/search/</guid>
        <description></description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
